Perfect timing.
완벽한 타이밍.
You want to know what happened to those missing students, right?
무슨 일이 일어났는지 알고 싶나요? 실종된 학생들에게요, 그렇죠?
Lorelei. Lorelei, are you okay?
로렐라이. 로렐라이, 괜찮아?
Lorelei.
로렐라이.
Loki!
로키!
Now we know someone’s working for Moriarty.
이제 우리는 알아요 누군가가 모리아티에서 일하고 있어요.
I have a student, Stein Alberts.
나에게는 Stein Alberts라는 학생이 있습니다.
When did anyone last see him?
그를 마지막으로 본 사람이 언제였나요?
This place has a rodent problem.
이 장소에는 설치류 문제가 있습니다.
If you can hear me...
내 말이 들리면...
knock, so we know where you are.
노크하시면 당신이 어디에 있는지 알 수 있습니다.
I wish it was always like this.
항상 그랬으면 좋겠습니다.
Before the tragedy occurs,
비극이 일어나기 전에
we can stop it.
우리는 그것을 멈출 수 있습니다.
Let’s be honest.
솔직하게 말해보자.
We both know who’s behind this incident.
우리 둘 다 이 사건의 배후가 누구인지 알고 있습니다.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Does it bother you that M may be tied to Stein's case?
그게 당신을 괴롭히나요? M이 Stein의 사건에 연루되어 있을 수도 있다는 거죠?
You know,
있잖아,
I’d rather you answer sarcastically than like that.
차라리 냉소적으로 대답해줬으면 좋겠어 그런 것보다.
I don’t know what’s going on in your head.
나는 당신의 머리 속에 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는지 모르겠습니다.
I thought you were smart enough to understand my distress
난 당신이 충분히 똑똑하다고 생각했어요 내 고통을 이해하기 위해
at the fact that my arch enemy was involved in the case.
내 최대의 적이라는 사실에 사건에 연루되어 있었습니다.
Do I still need to explain that?
그걸 제가 아직도 설명해야 하나요?
I just wanted to hear it directly from you,
그냥 듣고 싶었어 당신에게서 직접
even if I already knew.
이미 알고 있었음에도.
Sometimes it helps to say how you feel
때로는 기분이 어떤지 말하는 것이 도움이 됩니다
instead of keeping it in.
보관하는 대신
Sorry, I didn’t mean to overhear your argument.
미안, 그런 뜻은 아니었어 당신의 주장을 엿듣기 위해.
It’s okay.
괜찮아요.
Rosetta, wait. Why are you here?
로제타, 잠깐만요. 당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
Do you have a case to bring up?
제기할 사건이 있나요?
Nope. I have a different agenda today.
아니요. 오늘은 다른 일정이 있어요.
Oh, okay. Have a seat.
아, 그래요. 앉으세요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Agenda?
의제?
What? Another boring ghost hunt?
무엇? 또 지루한 유령 사냥이요?
Or do you have something more thrilling to offer?
아니면 뭔가 가지고 있나요? 제안하는 것이 더 스릴 있습니까?
I want to join the Q.E.D. Club!
Q.E.D에 가입하고 싶습니다. 클럽!
I saw how cool you guys were yesterday.
어제 너희들이 얼마나 멋진지 봤어.
So I decided to join too.
그래서 나도 합류하기로 결정했다.
You still have space for one or two more members, right?
아직 공간이 있어요 멤버 한두 명 정도 더요, 그렇죠?
Well, I’m just the Vice President, so you can review her application.
글쎄요, 저는 단지 부사장일 뿐입니다. 그녀의 지원서를 검토할 수 있도록 말이죠.
We don’t take just anyone as a club member.
우리는 아무나 데려가지 않아요 클럽 회원으로서.
Loki!
로키!
Especially, the likes of you.
특히 당신 같은 사람은요.
The likes of me?
내가 좋아하는 것?
Why? What’s wrong with me?
왜? 나에게 무슨 문제가 있습니까?
First of all...
우선...
you believe in ghosts.
당신은 유령을 믿습니다.
We can’t have someone
우리는 누군가를 가질 수 없어
who believes in nonsense.
말도 안되는 것을 믿는 사람.
You have to have something to believe in!
믿을만한 것이 있어야합니다!
You know what? Then, don’t!
그거 알아? 그렇다면 하지 마세요!
Drop it! Your loss!
버려라! 당신의 손실!
Rosetta!
로제타!
Loki, why did you have to be such a jerk?
로키, 왜 그렇게 멍청하게 굴어야 했나요?
You could’ve said it nicely without insults.
좋게 말할 수도 있었잖아 모욕하지 않고.
We don’t need excess baggage in the club.
클럽에는 초과 수하물이 필요하지 않습니다.
How would she contribute?
그녀는 어떻게 기여할 것인가?
Watch?
보다?
Clap?
박수?
Just say, "Cool"?
그냥 "멋져"라고 말할까요?
Every member should have a role to play.
모든 구성원은 각자 맡은 역할이 있어야 합니다.
Okay?
좋아요?
Then why did you force me to join here?
그럼 왜 나한테 여기에 합류하라고 강요한 거야?
I’m not even good at investigation or deduction.
난 착하지도 않아 조사 또는 공제 시.
I asked you specifically
내가 구체적으로 물어봤어
to be a chronicler of the club’s adventures.
연대기가 되다 클럽의 모험.
So don’t worry,
그러니 걱정하지 마세요.
your role benefits the club, even if you’re not that good.
귀하의 역할은 클럽에 도움이 되며, 비록 당신이 그렇게 좋지 않더라도.
But Rosalinda...
하지만 로잘린다는...
nothing.
아무것도 아님.
It’s Rosetta!
로제타입니다!
And another thing, Loki, it’s not really because...
그리고 또 한 가지, 로키, 꼭 그런 건 아니거든요...
Let’s go!
갑시다!
Oh, my gosh! This is so gory!
오, 맙소사! 이건 정말 피투성이야!
It seems like we have a new case to solve.
해결해야 할 새로운 사건이 생긴 것 같습니다.
♪ Shadows ♪
♪ 그림자 ♪
♪ in the dark are crawling. ♪
♪ 어둠 속에서 기어 다니고 있습니다. ♪
♪ Keeping watch and barring your way. ♪
♪ 감시하고 길을 막으세요. ♪
♪ As if the line could not be crossed. ♪
♪ 선을 넘을 수 없는 것처럼. ♪
♪ To every scream and every tremor. ♪
♪ 모든 비명과 모든 떨림에. ♪
♪ These walls remain the only witness. ♪
♪ 이 벽은 유일한 증인으로 남아있습니다. ♪
♪ Every noise is etched in here. ♪
♪ 모든 소음이 여기에 새겨져 있습니다. ♪
♪ Like fire and ammunition for your memory. ♪
♪ 불과 탄약처럼 당신의 기억을 위해. ♪
♪ Heed the warnings. ♪
♪ 경고에 귀를 기울이세요. ♪
♪ The threats poised to strike. ♪
♪ 위협이 공격을 준비하고 있습니다. ♪
♪ For this world ♪
♪ 이 세상을 위해 ♪
♪ is not what you imagined. ♪
♪당신이 상상했던 것과는 다릅니다. ♪
♪ Heed the warnings. ♪
♪ 경고에 귀를 기울이세요. ♪
♪ Open up your eyes. ♪
♪ 눈을 떠보세요. ♪
♪ For this world ♪
♪ 이 세상을 위해 ♪
♪ is not what you imagined. ♪
♪당신이 상상했던 것과는 다릅니다. ♪
♪ Heed the warnings. ♪
♪ 경고에 귀를 기울이세요. ♪
Catherine Del Rosario.
캐서린 델 로사리오.
But we might not need your help anymore
하지만 더 이상 당신의 도움이 필요하지 않을 수도 있습니다
since this is being treated as a suspected suicide.
이건 치료중이니까 자살 혐의로.
What are the chances that an individual taking their own life
기회는 무엇입니까 개인이 스스로 목숨을 끊는 것
by jumping off a height
높은 곳에서 뛰어내려
would land face up on the ground?
땅바닥에 앞면이 보이도록 착륙할까요?
Good point. Good point.
좋은 지적이다. 좋은 지적이다.
She didn’t jump.
그녀는 점프하지 않았습니다.
She was pushed.
그녀는 밀려났습니다.
Chief, may I?
국장님, 그래도 될까요?
The perfume on the handkerchief smells like a man’s.
손수건에 묻은 향수 남자 냄새가 난다.
It couldn't be the victim's, it could belong to someone else.
피해자의 것이 아닐 수 없습니다. 그것은 다른 사람의 것일 수도 있습니다.
Looks like she grabbed this from the one who pushed her.
그 사람이 이걸 움켜쥔 것 같아 그녀를 밀었던 사람에게서.
Sir.
선생님.
This isn’t suicide.
이것은 자살이 아닙니다.
This is murder.
이것은 살인이다.
And thanks to that handkerchief...
그리고 그 손수건 덕분에...
I think I know who did it.
누가 그랬는지 알 것 같아요.
Will this ever end?
이것이 끝날까요?
No matter how many corpses I see, I’ll never get used to it.
시체가 아무리 많아도 결코 익숙해지지 않을 것입니다.
So...
그럼...
what do you think about the case?
그 사건에 대해 어떻게 생각하세요?
Is it murder or suicide?
살인인가, 자살인가?
Why are you still asking me?
왜 아직도 나한테 묻는 거야?
Haven’t you already come to a conclusion?
이미 결론을 내리지 않았나요?
Besides, you said I’m not good at deduction.
게다가 말했잖아 저는 추리를 잘 못해요.
And I’m just the club’s chronicler anyway.
그리고 어쨌든 나는 단지 클럽의 연대기 기자일 뿐입니다.
I still want to know your opinion...
아직도 당신의 의견을 알고 싶습니다...
and if you agree with my deduction.
그리고 당신이 내 공제에 동의한다면.
I’d be surprised if you think otherwise.
당신이 다르게 생각한다면 나는 놀랄 것입니다.
Well, I...
음, 난...
I think the chief is right.
팀장님 말씀이 맞는 것 같아요.
Catherine ended her own life.
캐서린은 자신의 삶을 마감했습니다.
Looks like we’re looking at this from different angles.
우리가 이걸 보고 있는 것 같아 다른 각도에서.
Are you saying that just to spite me?
그냥 나를 괴롭히려고 그런 말을 하는 거야?
Is this you trying to prove
이걸 증명하려는 건가요
that you can also be a detective on your own merits?
너도 탐정이 될 수 있다는 걸 네 장점으로?
Now that I’ve told you my opinion, you’re just contradicting me.
이제 내 의견을 말씀드렸으니, 당신은 단지 나에게 모순되는 것뿐입니다.
You shouldn’t even be asking me anymore.
더 이상 나한테 묻지도 마세요.
Why do you think your opinion is more valid than mine?
왜 당신의 의견이라고 생각합니까? 내 것보다 더 유효합니까?
Let’s compare notes.
메모를 비교해 보겠습니다.
The victim was smiling when she fell.
피해자는 넘어질 때 웃고 있었다.
If she was pushed, whether intentionally or by accident,
만약 그녀가 밀렸다면, 의도적이든 우연이든
shouldn’t her expression show surprise?
그녀의 표정이 놀라움을 나타내야 하지 않겠습니까?
You’re making a grand assumption
당신은 엄청난 가정을 하고 있어요
out of a tiny, and probably insignificant detail.
아주 작은 것에서, 아마도 사소한 세부 사항 일 것입니다.
Maybe she’s just happy with the guy she’s with.
어쩌면 그녀는 단지 행복할지도 모릅니다 같이 있는 남자랑.
Not knowing he was going to kill her,
그가 그녀를 죽일 것이라는 사실을 모르고,
which is why she smiled.
그래서 그녀는 미소를 지었다.
Besides, how can you explain
게다가 어떻게 설명할 수 있나요
she’s holding someone else’s handkerchief?
그 사람이 다른 사람의 손수건을 들고 있다고요?
You’re right!
당신 말이 맞아요!
This handkerchief might be the clue to finding out who pushed her.
이 손수건이 단서일지도 몰라 누가 그녀를 밀어냈는지 알아내기 위해.
Or maybe that’s just what she wants us to think.
아니면 어쩌면 그것이 바로 그녀가 우리가 생각하기를 원하는 것입니다.
Oh, so you’re not giving up, huh?
아, 포기하는 건 아니겠죠?
Go on...
계속하세요...
entertain me with your theory.
당신의 이론으로 나를 즐겁게 해주세요.
Maybe she wants it to look like it was murder.
어쩌면 그녀가 그걸 원할 수도 있지 살인인 것처럼 보이려고요.
To frame the guy she was with.
그녀와 함께 있던 남자를 모함하기 위해.
But the police declared that the cause is self-inflicted.
하지만 경찰은 선언했다. 원인은 자기 자신에게 있다는 것입니다.
If no one pointed out that it was murder, her plan would fail.
살인이라고 아무도 지적하지 않는다면 그녀의 계획은 실패할 것이다.
Maybe she’s counting on someone
아마도 그녀는 누군가를 믿고 있는 것 같아요
with superb deductive skills to disprove it.
뛰어난 추리력으로 그것을 반증하기 위해.
You mean someone like me?
나 같은 사람 말이에요?
Oh, what's up? What’s your theory on what happened?
아, 무슨 일이야? 무슨 일이 일어났는지에 대한 당신의 이론은 무엇입니까?
Chief, it seems like Lorelei and I have different opinions.
과장님, 저랑 로렐라이 같군요 다른 의견을 가지고 있습니다.
I’m afraid we have to pursue two angles of this case separately.
유감스럽게도 우리는 두 가지 각도를 추구해야 합니다 이 경우는 별도로.
And we also have to invite the owner of the handkerchief.
그리고 우리도 초대해야 해 손수건의 주인.
This is going to be an interesting deduction showdown.
이것은 될 것입니다 흥미로운 공제 대결.
And I’m gonna prove to you that you’re wrong.
그리고 나는 당신에게 증명할 것입니다 당신이 틀렸다는 것.
Seriously?
진지하게?
Is it more important for you to prove me wrong than know the truth?
당신에게는 그것이 더 중요합니까? 진실을 아는 것보다 내가 틀렸다는 것을 증명하기 위해?
As if someone’s death is just a game to you.
마치 누군가의 죽음처럼 당신에게 그것은 단지 게임일 뿐입니다.
Guys, this is Leo Dacillo.
여러분, 레오 다실로입니다.
The boyfriend of the deceased.
고인의 남자친구.
Ex-boyfriend.
전 남자친구.
Cath and I have been broken up for a long time.
캐스와 나는 헤어졌어 오랫동안.
What do you need from me?
나한테 필요한 게 뭐야?
Is this handkerchief yours?
이 손수건은 당신 것인가요?
Yes, it’s mine.
응, 내 꺼야.
But that handkerchief’s been missing for a while.
그런데 그 손수건은 한동안 실종되었습니다.
Catherine was holding this,
캐서린이 이걸 들고 있었어
when she fell down and died.
그녀가 넘어져 죽었을 때.
Hold on.
기다리다.
Do you think I’m the one who pushed Catherine to her death?
내가 바로 그 사람이라고 생각하나요? 누가 캐서린을 죽음으로 몰아넣었나요?
We’re looking at that possibility.
우리는 그 가능성을 보고 있습니다.
Like I said, that handkerchief’s been missing for a long time!
아까 말했듯이 그 손수건은 오랫동안 실종되었습니다!
Catherine and I have been broken up for two months.
캐서린과 나는 헤어졌어 두 달 동안.
I was the one who broke up with her, but she still hasn’t accepted it.
그 사람과 헤어진 건 나였어. 하지만 그녀는 아직 그것을 받아들이지 않았습니다.
So...
그럼...
you got fed up.
넌 질렸어.
And in your anger, you could’ve pushed her.
그리고 당신의 분노 속에서, 당신은 그녀를 밀어낼 수도 있었습니다.
Then you made it look like she jumped on her own, right?
그럼 당신은 다음과 같이 만들었습니다 그 사람 혼자 뛰어내린 거 맞죠?
I could never do that!
난 절대 그럴 수 없어!
If you're not guilty,
당신이 무죄라면,
what were you doing there in the first place?
거기서 뭐하고 있었어? 처음에는?
Catherine asked to meet me.
캐서린이 나를 만나자고 했어요.
She’d been bugging me with messages for a while,
그녀는 나를 괴롭혔어요 잠시 동안 메시지와 함께
so I finally agreed just to make her stop.
그래서 나는 마침내 그녀를 멈추게 하기로 동의했습니다.
She said she wanted closure
폐쇄를 원한다고 하더군요
about our breakup.
우리 이별에 대해서.
When I got there,
거기 도착했을 때,
she suddenly jumped backward.
그녀는 갑자기 뒤로 뛰어올랐다.
I got scared, so I ran.
무서워서 도망쳤어요.
This is the last time, Catherine.
이번이 마지막이에요, 캐서린.
What more closure do you need?
더 이상 어떤 종결이 필요합니까?
Catherine?
캐서린?
What’s happening to you?
무슨 일이 일어나고 있나요?
Catherine, no!
캐서린, 안돼!
Oh, no!
안 돼!
What is happening? What's that?
무슨 일이 일어나고 있나요? 그게 뭐야?
Your handkerchief is the evidence we’re holding on to.
당신의 손수건 우리가 붙잡고 있는 증거입니다.
And the fact that you were the last person she spoke to before she fell.
그리고 당신이 마지막 사람이었다는 사실 그녀는 넘어지기 전에 이야기를 나눴습니다.
If Leo really pushed Catherine,
만약 레오가 정말로 캐서린을 밀었다면,
shouldn’t one or both of his hands have made contact with her skin or clothes?
한 손이나 두 손 모두 있으면 안 된다 피부나 옷에 접촉한 적이 있습니까?
Right?
오른쪽?
Can we confirm that through fingerprint analysis?
우리는 그것을 확인할 수 있습니까? 지문분석을 통해?
Lifting fingerprints from clothes is possible...
옷에서 지문 채취 가능해요...
but difficult.
하지만 어렵다.
One way is if the person who pushed her had sweaty or oily hands.
한 가지 방법은 그녀를 밀었던 사람이 손이 땀에 젖거나 기름기가 많았습니다.
If VMD picks something up, palm print analysis is possible.
VMD가 뭔가를 포착하면, 장문분석이 가능합니다.
And with that,
그리고
we’ll know if someone really pushed her or not.
누군가가 있다면 우리는 알게 될 것입니다 정말로 그녀를 밀었는지 아닌지.
VMD?
VMD?
Vacuum Metal Deposition.
진공 금속 증착.
Alright, I’ll have the victim’s uniform examined
알았어, 내가 할게 피해자 유니폼 검사
for palm print impressions
장문 인상을 위해
but we don’t have the equipment for that.
하지만 우리에겐 그럴 만한 장비가 없어요.
I’ll have it sent to the police commission’s forensics department.
경찰에 보내도록 할게요 위원회의 법의학 부서.
Can we get prints from both of your hands?
양손에서 지문을 채취할 수 있나요?
If that’s what will prove I’m innocent,
그것이 내가 결백하다는 것을 증명하는 것이라면,
then no problem.
그러면 문제 없습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Wanna bet what the result’s gonna be?
결과가 어떻게 나올지 내기하고 싶나요?
This isn’t a game, okay?
이건 게임이 아니야, 알았지?
This kind of situation shouldn’t be turned into a bet.
이런 상황 내기로 전환되어서는 안 된다.
A human life was lost, Loki.
인간의 생명이 사라졌어요, 로키.
These are the results.
결과는 다음과 같습니다.
No palm prints from the suspect were found on the victim’s uniform.
용의자의 장문도 없어 피해자의 유니폼에서 발견됐다.
Yes! I knew it!
예! 나는 그것을 알고 있었다!
Sorry. That was too much.
죄송합니다. 너무 과했어요.
I didn’t mean to celebrate, but...
축하할 생각은 없었지만...
I’m putting this on the blog, my theory was right, and you were wrong.
블로그에 이런 내용을 올리고 있는데, 내 이론은 옳았고 당신은 틀렸어요.
So whether you admit it or not, I can be a detective too.
그러니 당신이 인정하든 안 하든, 나도 탐정이 될 수 있다
Of course!
물론!
But not on my level.
하지만 내 수준은 아니다.
To be perfectly honest,
솔직히 말하면,
I also considered your suicide-to-frame-someone angle.
나도 고려했다 자살하여 누군가를 모함하는 각도.
But I didn’t tell you right away,
하지만 바로 말하지는 않았어요
because sometimes it helps
가끔은 도움이 되니까
when we see things differently to lets us cover every possibility.
우리가 사물을 다르게 볼 때 모든 가능성을 다룰 수 있게 해주세요.
Anyway,
어쨌든,
before you gloat or anything,
기분이 좋아지기 전에,
I just wanted to explain why I didn’t accept Rosario in the club.
그냥 설명하고 싶었어 내가 클럽에서 로사리오를 받아들이지 않은 이유.
It’s Rosetta, Loki!
로제타야, 로키!
Is it really that hard to remember?
정말 기억하기가 그렇게 어렵나요?
As I was saying...
내가 말했듯이...
being part of the club and by extension,
클럽의 일원이 되어 더 나아가
being close to me has proven to be dangerous.
나와 가까이 있는 것 위험한 것으로 판명되었습니다.
You experienced it last week when you were abducted.
지난주에 경험하셨잖아요 납치됐을 때.
You became a liability to me.
당신은 나에게 빚이 되었습니다.
But don’t get me wrong,
하지만 오해하지 마세요.
I value your presence
나는 당신의 존재를 소중하게 생각합니다
particularly when you tried to stop me from melting that fake janitor.
특히 네가 날 막으려고 했을 때 가짜 관리인을 녹이는 것부터요.
If you hadn’t been there,
그곳에 가보지 않았다면
I probably would’ve finished him off.
나는 아마 그를 끝내었을 것입니다.
No! Loki, that’s enough!
아니요! 로키, 그거면 충분해!
Please.
제발.
Think about this.
이것에 대해 생각해보십시오.
So you see...
보시다시피...
I can’t add another liability.
다른 책임을 추가할 수 없습니다.
Unless the applicant,
신청자가 아닌 이상,
can protect himself or herself without my help.
자신을 보호할 수 있다 내 도움 없이.
I failed to protect Rhea before.
나는 이전에 레아를 보호하지 못했습니다.
I don’t want that to happen to you.
나는 그런 일이 당신에게 일어나는 것을 원하지 않습니다.
I understand that.
나는 그것을 이해합니다.
Can you please try to be a little bit gentler next time?
제발 그렇게 되도록 노력해 주실 수 있나요? 다음번엔 좀 더 부드럽게?
You don’t have to be rude.
무례하게 굴 필요는 없습니다.
Maybe it’s because of M.
아마도 M 때문일지도 모르겠네요
Whenever I hear that single letter,
그 한 글자를 들을 때마다
or even the full codename Moriarty, I get triggered.
아니면 전체 코드명 Moriarty도요. 나는 방아쇠를 당겼다.
I can sometimes lose my cool
가끔은 냉정함을 잃을 수도 있어
because of him.
그 사람 때문에.
Anyway,
어쨌든,
speaking of that monster...
그 괴물 얘기가 나와서 말인데...
I’ll give you something.
내가 당신에게 뭔가를 줄 것이다.
Hey.
여기요.
It’s not even my birthday yet.
아직 내 생일도 아닌데.
What’s this?
이건 뭐야?
Just open it and see for yourself.
그냥 열어서 직접 확인해 보세요.
A ballpen?
볼펜?
That’s no ordinary pen.
평범한 펜이 아니네요.
It’s a stunning device disguised as a pen that you can bring anywhere.
펜으로 위장한 놀라운 장치입니다. 어디든 가지고 갈 수 있다는 것.
I had that made by someone I know who’s great with inventions.
아는 사람이 만든거 있었는데 발명품을 잘 다루는 사람.
Lorelei...
로렐라이...
we don’t know when Moriarty or his agents will strike again.
모리어티가 언제인지는 모르겠지만 그렇지 않으면 그의 대리인이 다시 파업할 것입니다.
But if and when that time comes,
하지만 그 때가 오면
you can use something to defend yourself.
자신을 방어하기 위해 무언가를 사용할 수 있습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Even if you can be a little rude,
조금 무례하게 굴더라도
you’re actually really thoughtful.
당신은 실제로 정말 사려 깊습니다.
Anyway,
어쨌든,
how do you use this?
이걸 어떻게 사용해요?
Well, all you need to do is press this button,
글쎄, 당신이해야 할 일은 모두 이 버튼을 누르시겠습니까?
and it will generate a high voltage electrical charge
그리고 그것은 생성됩니다 고전압 전하
that can immobilize anyone who...
누구든지 움직이지 못하게 할 수 있는...
Sorry.
죄송합니다.
I didn’t know the stun pen would be that powerful.
스턴펜은 몰랐는데 그만큼 강력할 것입니다.
Be careful when using the stun pen.
스턴펜을 사용할 때는 주의하세요.
Don’t use it on any nonsense.
말도 안되는 일에 사용하지 마십시오.
Okay, fine.
알았어, 알았어.
By the way...
그런데...
I need to visit Rhea’s tomb.
레아의 무덤을 방문해야 해요.
It’s her birthday next week.
다음 주가 그녀의 생일이에요.
You can come if you want.
원하시면 오셔도 됩니다.
Sure.
확신하는.
♪ The silence is deafening ♪
♪ 침묵이 귀를 먹먹하게 만드네요 ♪
♪ I can’t feel you anymore. ♪
♪ 더 이상 당신을 느낄 수 없어요. ♪
♪ Just staring into the distance. ♪
♪ 그저 먼 곳을 바라보고 있을 뿐입니다. ♪
♪ My heart has grown weary. ♪
♪ 마음이 지쳐버렸어요. ♪
♪ And now, I face the truth. ♪
♪ 그리고 지금, 나는 진실을 마주하고 있습니다. ♪
♪ That you’re really gone. ♪
♪ 당신이 정말 가버렸다는 걸요. ♪
♪ The question is... ♪
♪ 질문은... ♪
♪ Who will let go first? ♪
♪ 누가 먼저 놔줄까요? ♪
♪ Will it be me or you. ♪
♪ 나일까요 아니면 당신일까요? ♪
♪ To finally end us. ♪
♪ 마침내 우리를 끝내려고요. ♪
♪ We can’t bring back what we had. ♪
♪ 우리는 우리가 가지고 있던 것을 되돌릴 수 없습니다. ♪
♪ Since the line was let go. ♪
♪ 줄이 풀렸으니까요. ♪
♪ Ready to walk away. ♪
♪ 떠날 준비가 되었습니다. ♪
♪ It’s all been drained. ♪
♪ 다 소진됐어요. ♪
♪ Our love and tears. ♪
♪ 우리의 사랑과 눈물. ♪
♪ We can’t bring back what we had. ♪
♪ 우리는 우리가 가지고 있던 것을 되돌릴 수 없습니다. ♪
♪ The meaning it once held. ♪
♪ 한때 가졌던 의미. ♪
♪ The happiness it meant. ♪
♪ 그것이 의미하는 행복입니다. ♪
♪ This time... ♪
♪ 이번에는... ♪
♪ Happy Birthday to you. ♪
♪ 생일 축하합니다. ♪
♪ Happy Birthday, Happy Birthday. ♪
♪ 생일 축하해요, 생일 축하해요. ♪
♪ Happy Birthday to you! ♪
♪ 생일 축하해요! ♪
Blow.
불다.
Did you like my surprise for you?
제가 당신을 위한 깜짝 선물을 좋아하셨나요?
It's unnecessary but I appreciate the effort.
불필요하다 하지만 노력에 감사드립니다.
I hope you liked the strawberry cake.
딸기 케이크가 마음에 드셨기를 바랍니다.
I just didn’t know what flavor you liked.
나는 당신이 어떤 맛을 좋아하는지 몰랐습니다.
Strawberry’s fine.
딸기는 괜찮아요.
Any cake is fine.
어떤 케이크든 괜찮습니다.
I don’t really have a favorite.
나는 정말로 좋아하는 것이 없습니다.
Then what cake did you have on your birthday last year?
그럼 무슨 케이크 먹었어? 작년 생일에?
I don’t celebrate birthdays.
나는 생일을 축하하지 않습니다.
People only invented birthdays to have an excuse to celebrate,
사람들은 생일만 발명했다 축하할 핑계를 마련하려고
and for big companies to use it.
그리고 대기업이 그것을 사용합니다.
Come on. Don’t be so pessimistic, okay?
어서 해봐요. 너무 비관적으로 생각하지 마세요, 그렇죠?
Then my gift for you is wasted.
그렇다면 당신을 위한 내 선물은 헛된 것입니다.
Here!
여기!
Happy birthday!
생일 축하해요!
Just consider this my friendship gift to you.
그냥 이걸 내 것으로 생각해 당신에게 우정의 선물을 드립니다.
- Just accept it. - Fine.
- 그냥 받아들이세요. - 괜찮은.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
We should celebrate your birthday again next year, okay?
우리는 축하해야 해 내년에도 네 생일이잖아, 알았지?
That’s still a long way off.
아직 멀었습니다.
We’ll be celebrating your birthday first.
우리는 당신의 생일을 먼저 축하할 것입니다.
If you remember the date.
날짜를 기억한다면.
Come on, look at the cake.
자, 케이크 좀 보세요.
-Rhea must be so special to you.
-레아는 당신에게 정말 특별하군요.
Since the line was let go.
줄이 풀린 이후로.
Ready to walk away.
떠날 준비가 되었습니다.
It’s all been drained.
모두 소진되었습니다.
Our love and tears.
우리의 사랑과 눈물.
We can’t bring back what we had.
우리는 가지고 있던 것을 되돌릴 수 없습니다.
Who will let go?
누가 놓아줄 것인가?
Let’s go.
갑시다.
We can’t bring back what we had.
우리는 가지고 있던 것을 되돌릴 수 없습니다.
What the hell are you doing here?
도대체 여기서 뭐하는 거야?
You really have the nerve to come here after everything that happened?
너 정말 여기 올 용기가 있구나 그 모든 일이 일어난 후에?
And you even brought the next person whom you will send to the grave?
그리고 다음 사람까지 데려왔잖아 누구를 무덤에 보내겠느냐?
I didn’t come here to trade barbs.
나는 미늘 거래를 위해 여기에 온 것이 아닙니다.
I came here to honor Rhea’s memory.
나는 레아의 기억을 기리기 위해 여기에 왔습니다.
And I hope you remember all your sins too.
그리고 당신도 당신의 모든 죄를 기억하길 바랍니다.
You must never forget the price Rhea had to pay for being close to you.
가격을 절대 잊어서는 안됩니다 레아는 당신과 가까워진 대가를 치러야 했습니다.
I know you hate me,
당신이 나를 싫어한다는 걸 알아요
but, please, save your anger for another day.
하지만 제발, 다른 날을 위해 분노를 저장하십시오.
- Hate? I despise you! - We're leaving.
- 싫어하다? 나는 당신을 경멸합니다! - 우리는 떠난다.
Don’t worry.
괜찮아요.
You can pay your respects without getting annoyed by my presence.
경의를 표하시면 됩니다 내 존재에 짜증내지 않고.
See you at school.
학교에서 만나요.
Why does Maggie hate you to the bone?
매기는 왜 당신을 뼛속까지 미워하나요?
Rhea was more than just a friend to her.
레아는 그녀에게 단순한 친구 그 이상이었습니다.
She treated her like a sister.
그녀는 그녀를 자매처럼 대했습니다.
She warned us not to involve ourselves with Moriarty.
그녀는 우리에게 경고했다 모리아티에게 연루되지 말라고.
But I didn’t listen.
하지만 나는 듣지 않았습니다.
And soon after,
그리고 곧
Rhea was killed.
레아가 살해당했습니다.
That’s why she blames me.
그래서 그녀는 나를 비난합니다.
And she reminds me about it every opportunity she gets.
그리고 그녀는 나에게 그것에 대해 상기시켜줍니다 그녀가 얻는 모든 기회.
Do you think she’ll ever forgive you?
그 사람이 당신을 용서할 거라고 생각하시나요?
Only time can tell.
오직 시간만이 알 수 있습니다.
Wait, did you bring the stun pen I gave you?
잠깐, 가져왔어? 내가 준 스턴펜?
- I brought it. - Okay. Good.
- 내가 가져왔어. - 좋아요. 좋은.
- It can be. - What's that?
- 그럴 수도 있지. - 그게 뭐죠?
- Oh, my Gosh!
- 오, 맙소사!
- Another dead body?
- 또 시체요?
- Oh, my God. It's a person? - Gosh, come on!
- 맙소사. 사람인가요? - 이런, 어서!
- So scary! - Yeah, I know!
- 너무 무서워요! - 네, 알아요!
Oh, my God, there's really a serial killer in this school.
아, 맙소사, 정말 있어요 이 학교의 연쇄 살인범.
Did you see where it came from?
그것이 어디서 왔는지 보셨나요?
From the 5th floor.
5층부터.
- Nothing, really. - I don't wanna know, but...
- 아무것도 없어요, 정말요. - 알고 싶지는 않지만...
Yes, right. It's so bad.
예, 그렇죠. 너무 나쁘다.
Did any of you see what happened?
무슨 일이 일어났는지 보신 분 계신가요?
- No.
- 아니. - 아니요.
- Do you know anything?
- 아는 게 있나요?
- What about you? - No.
- 당신은 어때요? - 아니요.
- Nothing.
- 아니. - 아무것도.
- Did any of you see what happened? - No one.
- 무슨 일이 일어났는지 본 사람 있나요? - 아무도 없어요.
Me.
나.
Your name, please?
당신의 이름은 무엇입니까?
Daniel Geronimo.
다니엘 제로니모.
Justin Ruiz was my friend, the guy who jumped.
저스틴 루이스는 내 친구였고, 뛰어내린 그 사람.
Can you tell us what happened?
무슨 일이 일어났는지 말해줄 수 있나요?
If I’d known he was going to jump, I would’ve stopped him right away.
그 사람이 뛰어내릴 줄 알았더라면, 나는 그를 즉시 막았을 것입니다.
I don’t know what went through his mind that made him do that.
그 사람의 마음이 어떻게 되었는지는 모르겠지만 그것이 그를 그렇게 하게 만들었습니다.
It’s still warm.
아직 따뜻해요.
And it smells like tea.
그리고 차 냄새가 나요.
Did he drink something before jumping?
점프하기 전에 뭔가 마셨나요?
I just found him here at the edge, looking down.
방금 여기 가장자리에서 그를 찾았어요 아래를 내려다 보면서.
I didn’t see him holding anything.
나는 그가 아무것도 들고 있는 것을 보지 못했습니다.
I didn’t see anyone else besides him.
그 사람 외에는 다른 사람을 본 적이 없습니다.
Strange.
이상한.
Lorelei,
로렐라이,
the teacup’s still warm.
찻잔이 아직 따뜻해요.
If he really had nothing with him when he went up,
그 사람이 정말 아무 것도 없었다면 그가 올라갔을 때,
then someone must’ve placed the cup here
그렇다면 누군가가 여기에 컵을 놓은 게 틀림없어
and made him drink the tea.
그리고 그에게 차를 마시게 했다.
But why?
그런데 왜?
Chief.
셰프.
This is happening way too often.
이런 일이 너무 자주 일어나고 있습니다.
Chief, we need a fingerprint analysis,
국장님, 지문 분석이 필요해요
and we need to find out what kind of tea the suspect made him drink.
그리고 우리는 차가 어떤 종류인지 알아내야 해요 용의자는 그에게 술을 마시게 했다.
It looks like she and Catherine had the same cause of death.
그 사람이랑 캐서린이랑 닮은 것 같아 사망 원인도 같았다.
We don’t need your help anymore. Leave this investigation to us.
더 이상 당신의 도움이 필요하지 않습니다. 이 조사는 우리에게 맡겨주세요.
Okay, Chief.
알았어, 국장님.
Justin Ruiz is my classmate.
Justin Ruiz는 내 반 친구입니다.
I know him. He’s not the type to hurt himself.
나는 그 사람을 알아요. 그는 자해하는 타입이 아니다.
Justin’s a very confident guy.
저스틴은 매우 자신감 넘치는 사람입니다.
A lot of people like him,
많은 사람들이 그를 좋아합니다.
especially since he’s on the school’s basketball varsity team.
특히 그 사람이 학교에 있기 때문에 농구 대표팀.
Justin was always cheerful, even in his social media posts.
저스틴은 언제나 쾌활했고, 그의 소셜 미디어 게시물에서도요.
He was especially looking forward to the championship game.
그는 특히 기대하고 있었다 챔피언십 게임에.
You know,
있잖아,
I’ve been reading all the comments about what happened to Justin.
댓글 다 읽어봤는데 저스틴에게 일어난 일에 대해서요.
They all say he’d never do that to himself.
그들은 모두 말한다 그는 결코 자기 자신에게 그런 짓을 하지 않을 것입니다.
I interviewed his classmates as well,
그의 반 친구들과도 인터뷰를 했어요
and they said the exact same thing.
그리고 그들은 똑같은 말을 했습니다.
So does that mean...
그렇다면...
foul play is possible?
반칙이 가능한가요?
Should we be suspicious of the guy we talked to earlier?
의심해 볼까요? 우리가 아까 얘기했던 그 남자 말이야?
Who?
WHO?
From that David guy?
그 데이비드 남자한테서요?
Daniel!
다니엘!
The one who said he tried to stop Justin from jumping.
라고 말한 사람 그는 저스틴이 뛰어내리는 것을 막으려고 했습니다.
But eye witnesses said that the victim jumped by himself.
하지만 목격자들은 말했다. 피해자가 스스로 뛰어내렸다는 것.
If he pushed him, someone should’ve seen it.
만약 그 사람이 그를 밀었다면, 누군가 그것을 봤어야 했어요.
Unless,
그렇지 않은 경우
he used some magic contraption to make him fall.
그는 마법의 장치를 사용했어요 그를 넘어지게 만들려고.
But there’s nothing suspicious from where he jumped.
하지만 의심스러운 건 하나도 없어 그가 뛰어내린 곳에서.
Is this the Q.E.D. Club?
Q.E.D인가요? 클럽?
If you’re familiar with English alphabet and you know how to read,
영어 알파벳에 익숙하다면 그리고 넌 읽을 줄 알잖아,
- the answer to your question is... - That’s us!
- 귀하의 질문에 대한 답변은 ... - 바로 우리야!
Is there anything we can help you with?
우리가 도와드릴 게 있나요?
I'm Wade Montalban.
저는 웨이드 몬탈반이에요.
I need your help.
당신의 도움이 필요해요.
One of our Photography Club members died.
사진 클럽 회원 중 한 명이 사망했습니다.
It’s still warm.
아직 따뜻해요.
It smells sweet.
달콤한 냄새가 나요.
Today is her birthday, isn't it?
오늘이 그녀의 생일이지 않나요?
Why don't we play a game to commemorate this day?
우리 게임하는 게 어때? 오늘을 기념하기 위해?
M.
M.
He's challenging me.
그는 나에게 도전하고 있습니다.
I’m curious as to why you came here to fetch us instead of the campus police?
여기 왜 왔는지 궁금해요 캠퍼스 경찰 대신 우리를 데려오라고요?
I read your blogs.
나는 당신의 블로그를 읽었습니다.
And I found out you’ve solved a lot of cases.
그리고 나는 알아냈다 당신은 많은 사건을 해결했습니다.
This one...
이건...
can you solve this case?
이 사건을 해결할 수 있나요?
Wait.
기다리다.
What makes you say it’s murder?
살인이라고 말하는 이유는 무엇입니까?
Doesn’t it look like self-harm at first?
얼핏 보면 자해처럼 보이지 않나요?
Serena and I go way back.
세레나와 나는 아주 멀리 돌아갑니다.
She thinks too highly of herself.
그녀는 자신을 너무 높게 생각합니다.
That's why...
그렇기 때문에...
she couldn’t have killed herself.
그녀는 자살할 수 없었습니다.
Does she like drinking tea?
그녀는 차 마시는 것을 좋아하나요?
What kind?
어떤 종류?
I know she’s not into tea.
나는 그녀가 차를 좋아하지 않는다는 것을 압니다.
I’ve never even seen her drink tea.
나는 그녀가 차를 마시는 것을 본 적이 없습니다.
We don’t even keep tea in the photography room.
우리는 차도 마시지 않는다 사진실에서.
Earlier, you said you found her like that.
앞서 당신은 그런 사람을 찾았다고 말했어요.
Could you tell us how this really happened?
실제로 어떻게 이런 일이 일어났는지 말씀해주실 수 있나요?
Which one should we choose for our poster?
우리 포스터로 어떤 것을 선택해야 할까요?
- Wait. - This.
- 기다리다. - 이것.
Oh, gosh.
아, 이런.
Serena, I’ll just be a sec.
세레나, 잠시만 기다리겠습니다.
- Is it okay? - Hurry!
- 괜찮아요? - 서두르다!
- Hurry up. Hurry up. - I'll be right back. Promise.
- 서둘러요. 서둘러요. - 금방 돌아올게요. 약속하다.
Don’t go sneaking off to the canteen, okay?
몰래 나가지 마세요 매점으로, 알았지?
When I got back, she was already covered in blood.
돌아왔을 때, 그녀는 이미 피로 뒤덮여 있었습니다.
Serena?
세레나?
Serena!
세레나!
Help!
돕다!
Lori, Loki,
로리, 로키,
are you guys magnets for bad luck?
너희들은 불운을 부르는 자석이야?
Chief,
서장님,
I think you should pay attention to the teacups.
주의를 기울이시면 될 것 같아요 찻잔까지.
Okay.
좋아요.
We’ll take it from here.
여기서부터 살펴보겠습니다.
We’ll keep you updated on this case and on Justin Ruiz as well.
이 사건에 대해 계속해서 알려드리겠습니다. 저스틴 루이즈도 그렇고.
Come in.
들어오세요.
Get this.
이것을 받으세요.
Here.
여기.
- Oh, there you go. Just keep writing. - Give me the rest of those papers too.
- 아, 그렇군요. 계속 쓰세요. - 나머지 서류도 나한테 주세요.
Have you ever wondered
궁금한 적 있으신가요
why those two were targeted by Moriarty, or one of his agents?
왜 그 두 사람이 표적이 되었는가 Moriarty, 아니면 그의 대리인 중 한 사람이요?
I mean..
내 말은..
What does he gain from killing an aspiring basketball player
그 사람이 살인을 해서 얻는 게 뭔데? 야심찬 농구선수
and a Photography Club member?
사진클럽 회원인가요?
I don't know.
모르겠습니다.
But these two cases
하지만 이 두 가지 경우
have one element in common.
한 가지 공통점이 있습니다.
The teacups.
찻잔.
His motive still escapes me.
그의 동기는 아직도 기억나지 않습니다.
Maybe he has one...
어쩌면 그 사람도 하나 갖고 있을지도 모르지...
or maybe he doesn't.
아니면 그렇지 않을 수도 있습니다.
Motive?
동기?
Who?
WHO?
Good afternoon.
좋은 오후에요.
Chief Gareth sent over...
가레스 추장이 보냈습니다...
the fingerprint analysis results
지문 분석 결과
from the teacups found at the crime scenes.
찻잔에서 범죄 현장에서 발견되었습니다.
Thank you, Officer Montreal.
감사합니다, 몬트리올 경관님.
Chief said to reach out if you need anything else.
팀장님이 연락하라고 하셔서 다른 것이 필요하다면.
That’s all. I’ll get going now.
그게 다야. 이제 가겠습니다.
- Thank you.
- 감사합니다.
There are no other fingerprints found on the teacups
다른 지문은 발견되지 않았습니다 찻잔 위에
or the pair of scissors
아니면 가위
except for the victims.
피해자 제외.
The campus police consider these as suicidal cases.
캠퍼스 경찰 이를 자살 사례로 간주하십시오.
Unless, evidence suggests otherwise.
증거가 달리 제시되지 않는 한.
Whoever is behind this...
이 배후에 누가 있든...
did a clean job.
깨끗한 일을 했습니다.
Belladonna!
벨라도나!
Huh?
뭐?
Belladonna.
벨라도나.
Traces of Belladonna were found in the teacup.
벨라도나의 흔적 찻잔에서 발견되었습니다.
And on the victim's body.
그리고 피해자의 몸에.
What's Belladonna?
벨라돈나란 무엇인가?
Belladonna is a poisonous plant
벨라도나는 독성이 있는 식물입니다
that has been used for medication since ancient times.
약으로 사용되었던 것 고대부터.
It also goes as a sinister name,
불길한 이름으로도 사용됩니다.
the devil’s berries.
악마의 열매.
And when ingested,
그리고 섭취되면
it can also cause vivid hallucinations and deliriums.
생생한 환각을 일으킬 수도 있습니다. 그리고 섬망.
And some use it...
그리고 일부는 그것을 사용합니다...
as a recreational drug.
기분전환용 약물로.
Hallucinations? Delirium? That's why!
환각? 섬망 상태? 그렇기 때문에!
Exactly!
정확히!
The culprit did not need to touch the victim's body
범인은 필요하지 않았다 피해자의 몸을 만지기 위해
to kill them.
그들을 죽이려고.
All he had to do was to offer them a cup of tea.
그가 해야 할 일은 모두 그들에게 차 한 잔을 권하기로 했습니다.
And once the poison kicks in...
그리고 일단 독이 들어오면...
it induces hallucinations that drive them to hurt themselves.
그것은 환각을 불러일으킨다 그것은 그들로 하여금 스스로 상처를 입게 만듭니다.
The culprit makes a suggestion...
범인이 제안을 합니다...
and the victim will do whatever he says.
피해자는 그가 말하는 대로 할 것입니다.
Come on, jump.
자, 뛰어내려라.
Actually,
실제로
it’s much more clever than hypnosis.
그것은 최면보다 훨씬 더 영리합니다.
And there’s a chance that suggestions won’t work.
그리고 기회가 있어요 그 제안은 작동하지 않습니다.
And if that happens,
그런 일이 발생하면
the poison will do its job and still kill the victim.
독이 제 역할을 할 것이다 그리고 여전히 피해자를 죽입니다.
Our culprit is creative.
우리의 범인은 창의적입니다.
His choice to use such an ingenious trick proves it.
그의 사용 선택 이런 기발한 트릭이 이를 증명한다.
He probably didn’t want to see someone dying in a boring way.
그 사람은 아마 누군가를 만나고 싶지 않았을 거야 지루하게 죽어가는 중.
Sorry,
죄송합니다.
that’s a bit of information overload.
그것은 약간의 정보 과부하입니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Let's take a break.
잠시 쉬자.
I’m gonna grab some coffee from the cafeteria first.
나 커피 좀 마실래 먼저 구내식당부터.
Do you want one?
하나 원하시나요?
Here’s your coffee.
여기 당신의 커피가 있습니다.
Be careful, it’s hot.
조심하세요, 더워요.
You know...
아시죠...
looks like there’s a strong chance our theories are right.
가능성이 크다고 본다 우리 이론이 맞아요.
But if the culprit handed the teacups to the victims,
하지만 범인이 건네면 피해자들에게 찻잔을,
how come there were no fingerprints on them?
지문은 왜 없지? 그들에게?
He could’ve used another trick.
그는 다른 트릭을 사용할 수도 있었습니다.
We need to think about it
생각해 볼 필요가 있어
if we want to prove our point to the police.
우리의 주장을 증명하고 싶다면 경찰에.
Tissue.
조직.
That’s it!
그게 다야!
The culprit handed them the teacups with a tissue,
범인이 건넨 건데요 티슈와 찻잔,
which is why there were no fingerprints.
그래서 지문이 없었어요.
Whoever the culprit is,
범인이 누구이든,
they’re really good at covering up their tracks.
정말 좋은데 그들의 흔적을 은폐하는 데.
Not necessarily.
반드시 그런 것은 아닙니다.
The first crime was messy.
첫 번째 범죄는 지저분했습니다.
The culprit didn’t expect anyone to interfere
범인은 예상하지 못했다 방해할 사람
before carrying out the crime.
범죄를 저지르기 전
He was almost got caught
그는 잡힐 뻔했다
by other students.
다른 학생들에 의해.
The second case, however,
그러나 두 번째 경우는
was almost flawless.
거의 완벽했습니다.
He left no trace of his crime...
그는 자신의 범죄 흔적을 전혀 남기지 않았습니다...
except for that teacup.
그 찻잔만 제외하고.
What about Catherine?
캐서린은 어떻습니까?
Her case might be connected to this.
그녀의 사건이 이것과 연관되어 있을 수도 있습니다.
Catherine no!
캐서린 안돼!
I don't think so.
그렇지 않은 것 같아요.
There’s a big gap between her and the next victims.
큰 격차가 있습니다 그녀와 다음 희생자 사이에.
That's why I truly believe that hers is an isolated case.
그렇기 때문에 나는 진심으로 믿는다. 그녀는 고립된 사례라는 것을요.
These next two cases are connected.
다음 두 경우는 서로 연결되어 있습니다.
They were victimized on the same day, and they were even classmates.
같은 날 피해자가 됐습니다. 그리고 그들은 심지어 동급생이기도 했습니다.
So what do you think of Leo?
그렇다면 레오에 대해 어떻게 생각하시나요?
That's why,
그래서
I think, this guy is not guilty.
내 생각엔 이 사람은 죄가 없는 것 같아.
It just so happened that he was meeting his girlfriend that day.
마침 그 사람이 만나고 있었어. 그날 그의 여자친구.
I’ve been trying to figure out the motive since earlier.
나는 알아내려고 노력해왔다 동기는 아까부터.
M wants to send a message to me today...
M이 오늘 나에게 메시지를 보내고 싶어합니다...
on Rhea’s birthday.
레아의 생일
He wants to make sure that I receive it.
그는 내가 그것을 받았는지 확인하고 싶어합니다.
But since the teacup accidentally broke,
하지만 실수로 찻잔이 깨졌기 때문에
the culprit needs to make another kill
범인은 또 다른 사람을 죽여야 해
to ensure that I got the message the second time around.
내가 메시지를 받았는지 확인하기 위해 두 번째로.
Therefore,
따라서
it just so happened that Serena became the victim,
방금 그런 일이 일어났어 세레나가 피해자가 되었다고
and Wade was the unlucky witness.
그리고 웨이드는 불행한 증인이었습니다.
So if Leo and Wade are both innocent,
따라서 Leo와 Wade가 모두 결백하다면
then the real culprit is...
그렇다면 진짜 범인은...
Daniel Geronimo.
다니엘 제로니모.
Wow, you actually got the name right for once!
와, 실제로 받으셨군요 이름이 딱 한 번!
Impressive.
인상적인.
I know you can solve this puzzle, Loki.
난 네가 이 퍼즐을 풀 수 있다는 걸 알아, 로키.
Looks like the warning to me was right.
나에게 경고한 것이 맞는 것 같습니다.
Once you got the police report,
경찰 신고서를 받으면,
you’d know I did all this
내가 이 모든 일을 했다는 걸 알겠지
and, more importantly, what I used.
그리고 더 중요한 것은 내가 사용한 것입니다.
I have your scandal.
나는 당신의 스캔들을 가지고 있습니다.
And if you don’t drink this,
그리고 이걸 마시지 않으면
I’ll make sure it gets out.
꼭 나올 수 있도록 할게요.
Who are you?
누구세요?
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
It doesn’t matter who I am.
내가 누구인지는 중요하지 않습니다.
Stay away from me.
나에게서 멀리 떨어져 있습니다.
What matters is I know
중요한 건 내가 아는 거야
about your secret relationship with Mr. Olinares.
당신의 비밀 연애에 대해 올리나레스 씨와 함께요.
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
I have evidence
증거가 있어요
that you two checked into a motel.
너희 둘이 모텔에 묵었다고.
So if I were you, I’d just drink this.
그러니까 내가 너라면 그냥 이걸 마실 것 같아.
Because if you don’t,
그렇지 않으면
I’ll leak the video of you two.
두 분의 영상을 유출하겠습니다.
And everyone will see your scandal.
그리고 모두가 당신의 스캔들을 보게 될 것입니다.
Is that all I have to do?
그게 내가 해야 할 전부야?
I just have to drink that?
꼭 마셔야 하는 걸까요?
Simple!
단순한!
Just drink this, and I won’t do what I said.
이것만 마시세요, 그리고 나는 내가 말한 대로 하지 않을 것이다.
And Catherine...
그리고 캐서린...
You both thought she wasn’t connected,
두 사람 모두 그녀가 연결되어 있지 않다고 생각했습니다.
but you were wrong.
하지만 당신은 틀렸어요.
She just wanted revenge
그녀는 단지 복수를 원했을 뿐이에요
and to frame Leo, so she did it.
레오를 모함하기 위해 그녀는 그렇게 했습니다.
I made her drink the tea too.
나는 그녀에게도 차를 마시게 했습니다.
Go jump.
점프하러 가세요.
Stab yourself,
스스로를 찔러보세요
using scissors.
가위를 사용하여.
For a murder suspect,
살인 용의자의 경우,
you’re pretty cocky.
당신은 꽤 건방지군요.
You’re not Moriarty.
당신은 모리어티가 아닙니다.
He’s a coward.
그는 겁쟁이입니다.
He hides behind lackeys like you.
그 사람은 당신 같은 부족한 사람들 뒤에 숨어 있어요.
It’s not time yet, Loki, for him to show himself to you.
아직은 때가 아니야, 로키. 그 사람이 당신에게 자신을 보여주기 위해.
I see.
알겠어요.
Can I send him a gift?
그에게 선물을 보내도 될까요?
Like a pen or something.
펜 같은 거요.
Don’t. Don’t do anything you’ll regret.
하지 않다. 후회할 일은 하지 마세요.
Are these for us?
이것이 우리를 위한 것인가요?
You want to murder us the same way you did the others, huh?
당신은 우리를 죽이고 싶어 다른 사람들도 마찬가지였지, 응?
If I wanted to kill you, I would’ve done it outright.
내가 당신을 죽이고 싶었다면, 나는 그것을 솔직하게했을 것입니다.
But Moriarty doesn’t want that.
하지만 모리어티는 그것을 원하지 않습니다.
He doesn’t even want a scratch on you.
그는 심지어 당신에게 긁힌 자국도 원하지 않습니다.
He’s so overprotective of me.
그 사람은 나를 너무 과잉보호해요.
What is he, my girlfriend or something?
그 사람이 뭔데, 내 여자친구니 뭐니?
This isn’t for the two of you.
이건 너희 둘을 위한 게 아니야.
Sorry, I didn’t bring another cup for your friend.
미안, 한 잔 더 안 가져왔어 당신의 친구를 위해.
This is for the two of us.
이것은 우리 둘을 위한 것입니다.
And what if I don’t choose?
그리고 내가 선택하지 않으면 어떻게 되나요?
What if I just walk out the door?
그냥 문밖으로 나가면 어떡하지?
Or what if I just knock you out right now?
아니면 지금 당장 당신을 쓰러뜨리면 어떻게 되나요?
You can try,
시도해 볼 수 있습니다.
so you’ll find out I’ve got two people waiting outside.
그래서 당신은 알게 될 것입니다 밖에는 두 사람이 기다리고 있어요.
And I’m sure you know what we can do to you
그리고 나는 당신이 알고 있다고 확신합니다 우리가 당신에게 무엇을 할 수 있나요
if you make the wrong move.
잘못 움직이면.
What do you think you’re doing?
당신은 무엇을 하고 있다고 생각하나요?
Sit!
앉다!
Sit.
앉다.
Let go of me!
날 놔줘!
I’m not going to kill you, Loki.
난 널 죽이지 않을 거야, 로키.
You'll just watch your partner bleed out in front of you.
당신은 당신의 파트너를 지켜볼 것입니다 당신 앞에서 피를 흘리십시오.
What makes you think I care about her?
내가 그녀에게 관심을 갖고 있다고 생각하는 이유는 무엇입니까?
I could just walk away from this room without getting any scratch.
난 그냥 이 방에서 나가도 돼 흠집 하나 없이.
Stop! Stop!
멈추다! 멈추다!
I thought you didn’t care.
나는 당신이 상관하지 않는다고 생각했습니다.
Can your conscience handle it, Loki?
네 양심이 감당할 수 있겠어, 로키?
Can you handle someone close to you getting dragged into this again?
가까운 사람을 다룰 수 있습니까? 또 이것에 끌려가는 거야?
Huh?
뭐?
Now, sit!
자, 앉아!
Now…
이제...
let’s have a drinking game.
술게임 하자.
Moriarty wants to test how good you really are at deduction.
모리아티는 시험해보고 싶어 당신은 정말 추론을 얼마나 잘하는지요.
So we’re going to play a drinking game.
그래서 우리는 술게임을 하려고 합니다.
One of them contains belladonna.
그 중 하나에는 벨라도나가 포함되어 있습니다.
And the other one is just regular tea.
그리고 다른 하나는 그냥 일반 차입니다.
I’ll let you choose.
선택하게 할게요.
And once you’ve chosen one, we drink at the same time.
그리고 하나를 선택하고 나면, 우리는 동시에 마신다.
Do you mind if I sniff the scent of these teas?
내가 냄새 맡아도 괜찮을까? 이 차 냄새요?
Go ahead, be my guest.
어서 내 손님이 되어주세요.
Better pray you chose the right cup.
올바른 컵을 선택하기를 기도하는 것이 좋습니다.
Let the game begin.
게임을 시작하자.
Let’s see who walks out of this room alive.
누가 나가는지 보자 이 방은 살아있습니다.
I have one question for you.
질문이 하나 있습니다.
Since this might be our last conversation we would ever have,
이게 우리 마지막 대화일지도 모르니까 우리는 그런 적이 있었을 거예요
I wanna know why Moriarty is so obsessed with me.
왜 모리어티인지 알고 싶어 나에게 너무 집착해요.
Mind telling me the reason?
이유를 말해봐도 될까요?
When your former partner died,
이전 파트너가 사망했을 때,
he was upset that you suddenly vanished off his radar.
그는 화가 났어요 당신이 갑자기 그의 레이더에서 사라졌다는 걸요.
But he got fired up again
그런데 그 사람이 또 화를 냈어요
when he heard you were involved in the case at the chemistry lab.
그가 당신이 연루됐다는 소식을 들었을 때 화학 실험실의 경우.
And the many other cases you meddled in.
그리고 당신이 개입한 다른 많은 사건들도요.
So I returned to his radar after that case?
그럼 그 사건 이후에 내가 그의 레이더로 돌아갔다는 건가요?
You meddled in his business again this academic year.
당신이 또 그 사람 일에 간섭했어요 이번 학년도.
One of the recent ones
최근 것 중 하나
was our kidnapping of the math prodigy found in an abandoned school building.
우리가 수학 천재를 납치한 거였어 버려진 학교 건물에서 발견되었습니다.
Our client ran into a problem.
우리 고객에게 문제가 생겼습니다.
So we found a way to make his wish come true,
그래서 우리는 방법을 찾았어요 그의 소원을 이루기 위해
to get that man out of his way.
그 사람을 방해하지 않으려면.
You’re just like us, at Q.E.D.?
Q.E.D.에서 당신도 우리와 똑같나요?
You also solve problems, but in a deadly way.
문제도 해결하시고, 하지만 치명적인 방법으로.
We just grant the wishes of students who need our help.
우리는 소원을 들어줄 뿐입니다 우리의 도움이 필요한 학생들.
And for the right price,
그리고 적절한 가격으로
we can do anything for them.
우리는 그들을 위해 무엇이든 할 수 있습니다.
If they want someone taken out,
누군가를 데려가기를 원한다면,
something stolen,
뭔가를 훔쳤어요
or information obtained,
또는 획득한 정보,
all of it, every request they make,
그 모든 것, 그들이 하는 모든 요청,
we pass it on to Moriarty,
우리는 그것을 Moriarty에게 전달합니다.
and he decides what we do next.
그리고 그는 우리가 다음에 무엇을 할지 결정합니다.
Just like his fictional namesake.
그의 허구의 이름과 같습니다.
He’s the mastermind,
그 사람이 주모자야,
and you’re the ones who carry it out.
그리고 당신은 그것을 수행하는 사람입니다.
Or he can be the director,
아니면 그가 감독이 될 수도 있어요,
and we're the actors.
그리고 우리는 배우입니다.
Have you ever seen him in person?
그를 직접 본 적이 있나요?
Do you know who Moriarty is?
모리어티가 누군지 아시나요?
Or what he looks like?
아니면 그 사람은 어떻게 생겼나요?
Or what his voice sounds like?
아니면 그의 목소리는 어떤가요?
I’m just a pawn on his chessboard.
나는 단지 그의 체스판 위의 졸일 뿐입니다.
Only the high-ranking members know who he is.
고위직 회원들만 그 사람이 누군지 알아요.
Lorelei!
로렐라이!
Rhea...
레아...
is that you?
그게 당신인가요?
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
Hey.
여기요.
Wake up, sleepy head.
일어나라, 졸린 머리야.
Loki!
로키!
You’re alive!
당신은 살아있습니다!
Good thing you’re awake. How are you feeling?
일어나서 다행이네요. 기분이 어때요?
My subconscious said that you're also crying?
내 잠재의식이 말했다 너도 울고 있다고?
Why would I cry over you?
내가 왜 당신 때문에 울겠습니까?
Anyway, take care, you guys. Loki. Especially you, Lorelei.
아무튼 조심하세요 여러분. 로키. 특히 당신, 로렐라이.
Wait, do you suspect the professor?
잠깐만요, 교수님을 의심하시나요?
Morayta...
모라이타...
is the Filipino version of Moriarty.
Moriarty의 필리핀 버전입니다.
Here’s Daniel Geronimo’s autopsy report.
다니엘 제로니모의 부검 보고서는 다음과 같습니다.
Just checking if i’m still alive?
내가 아직 살아 있는지 확인하는 건가요?
Or are you here to finish the job?
아니면 일을 끝내러 여기에 오셨나요?
It’s ironic, because I did warn you, stop looking for M.
아이러니하네요. 제가 경고했거든요. M 그만 찾으세요.